findagrave.com 2017-06-24

# Find A Grave - Privacy Statement

**Last updated on 23 May, 2014**

This Privacy Statement discusses the collection, use, storage and disclosure of your personal information by Find A Grave, Inc., 1300 W Traverse Parkway, Lehi, UT 84043, United States (referred also as "Find A Grave", "us", "our" or "we") and applies to visitors and members registering on the websites and the mobile websites and applications that we operate worldwide, including FindAGrave.com and the Find A Grave mobile application and which link directly to this Privacy Statement (collectively, the "Websites"). For previous versions of the Privacy Statement click here.

### Our Privacy Commitment

Find A Grave's mission is to find, record and present final disposition information from around the world as a virtual cemetery experience. This may involve the collecting, processing, storing and sharing of personal information. We are committed to ensuring that this is done in a responsible, transparent and secure environment that fosters your trust and confidence. As part of our commitment to you, we have developed this Privacy Statement to describe how we gather and use the information we receive from you on the Websites. Please review the information below to familiarize yourself with our policies.

In this Privacy Statement, we, Find A Grave, provide information on what personal information is collected and why as well as how we use the personal information to provide you with a personalized, relevant, user-friendly experience on the Websites. As a reminder, by registering with any of the Websites you are becoming part of the "Ancestry Community" a collaborative resource in which the users of the Websites and other websites and platforms owned or operated by Find A Grave and its group companies ("Group Companies") (including such sites as ancestry.com, ancestry.co.uk, ancestry.com.au, archives.com, ancestry.ca) participate. Please be aware that some sites may have some additional specific policies or different functionality and you should read and / or understand these before using the relevant services.

This Privacy Statement should be read in conjunction with the Terms of Service.

1\. What personal information does Find A Grave collect?  
2\. How does Find A Grave use your personal information?  
3\. Will Find A Grave disclose any of your personal information to third parties?  
4\. What about non-personal information, "cookies" and social media features?  
5\. Managing Your Privacy Settings  
6\. How do you report, change or delete personal information about you or your family  
7\. Security  
8\. Changes, updates and consent  
9\. Contact us about privacy  

**1\. What personal information does Find A Grave collect from or about you?**

We only collect information we believe is necessary for the legitimate business interests of Find A Grave or its Group Companies. You do not have to provide us with your personally identifiable information but, if you do not provide us with the information we require, we may not be able to provide you with our products or services, or certain features of them.

You may also be able to deal with us without identifying yourself (i.e. anonymously or by using a pseudonym) in certain circumstances, such as by not using your real name as your "Public" or "Screen" name.

Here is a list of the type of personal information we request, collect or you provide:

  1. Name, contact information and payment details: To gain access to certain parts of the Websites it will be necessary to create a registered user account by providing your name, email address and a password. You will also be asked to provide a "Public" or "Screen" name which will be used to identify you to other users on the Website. We will also ask for your payment details (such as a credit or debit card number) if you pay to sponsor a memorial or purchase other services or products from Find A Grave. 
  2. Your background and interests: As a user of the Websites, you can also choose to share certain information about yourself, such as your location, home page, and background and interests with other users by adding to your member profile - the amount of this type of information that you add to your member profile is entirely your choice. 
  3. Your family and others: You may also post additional personal information about yourself and others in the course of using our Websites, e.g., adding a photo or bio to an obituary or a memorial or sharing it with someone through the Websites. Similarly, others may post personal information about you or your family members in the course of using our Websites.

If you post information about living persons, you must inform them and seek their consent. If the person is under the legal age to enter into agreements, you must ask for the consent of the parent or guardian of that person. In all cases, you must make the implications of the consent clear to the person (or, if applicable, to the parent/guardian) and notify them of our Privacy Statement and where it can be found before posting or providing their personal information. In such case, you warrant that the consent is truthful, correct and complete and that you are responsible for providing the personal data to Find A Grave.

Find A Grave also publishes records on its Websites that it has obtained from many sources, with appropriate consents and permissions where relevant. Some of these records may contain personal information that relates to living individuals, usually from public record sources. While some of this information may indirectly reveal certain sensitive information about you (such as nationality and/or ethnic origin), please note that Find A Grave does not specifically request, or intend to collect, any sensitive personal data from users. If we specifically request sensitive personal data from you, we will inform you and obtain your express written consent prior to the collection of such data.

  4. Your opinions and comments: If you participate in community discussions, chats, communications between us or between you and other members, or during any disputes you may have with us or other users, we will capture that information. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. 
  5. Your use of the Websites: While you use our Websites, we may collect information based on your interaction with our Websites or from the devices or computers you use to access the Websites, including web log information, page views, searches conducted and IP addresses which may identify you. We also collect information about your activity on the Websites such as when you post photos, bookmark gravestones, or contribute any other content on the Websites. 
  6. Location data. You can choose to provide your location to us in conjunction with our photo Volunteer program. In addition, we collect and store information regarding the searches you conduct on the Websites, which include the locations you enter into the search fields. If you access the Websites using a mobile device we also collect location data directly from your device with your consent via your device settings. 
  7. Mobile device data: If you access the Website using a mobile device (for example, phones, tablets, iPads etc.), we collect mobile device identifiers such as the device type, IP address and the operating system which may identify you. We will also occasionally send you push notifications to provide you information about our services. You may opt-out of these notifications at the device level. 

**2\. How Does Find A Grave use your personal information?**

  1. To provide the Service: We use your personal information to fulfill the purposes for which you have provided the personal information, such as to provide appropriate search results and facilitate communications with other users. We also use your personal information to provide you with relevant information such as information about product and Website updates, informational updates that you have requested through the Websites (including photo requests, if you have indicated that you want to be a photo volunteer), or to address customer service needs and requests. So that you get the most out of the service we will also use your personal information to enable you and other Find A Grave members to contact each other (on an anonymous basis if you choose). 
  2. Verification: We may use your personal information to verify your identity so that you can carry out transactions through the Websites, such as changing your account information, retrieving forgotten login information or completing financial transactions relating to payments you make online. 
  3. For internal business purposes: In order to improve the Websites (or to develop new products and services), we may use your personal information for data analysis, studying how our Websites are used, identifying usage trends and determining the effectiveness of promotional campaigns. 
  4. To communicate with you: Find A Grave may communicate with you for the purpose of informing you of issues with your account or changes to Find A Grave or of any Find A Grave-related products and services. Our communication with you will generally be via email, but may be made via telephone, direct mail or another method of communication in select circumstances. We may also contact you via email, telephone, direct mail or another method of communication about promotional offers from Find A Grave, its Group Companies or third parties trusted by Find A Grave. If you do not want to receive these non-essential promotional communications, you may opt out at any time by using the unsubscribe link listed in the email or by contacting us at info@findagrave.com. 
  5. To distribute advertisements: Find A Grave strives to display relevant advertisements to you both on our Websites and elsewhere on the Internet. To that end, we use aggregated demographic information (such as women between the ages of 45-60), anonymized data compared to data from third parties, or the placement of cookies (as discussed in more detail in Section 5 below). In these ways, Find A Grave can display relevant ads to appropriate users either on our Websites or on third party websites. Find A Grave does not sell, rent or otherwise distribute the personal information you provide us to these advertisers unless you have given us your consent to do so.

Find A Grave may use some third parties to show you Find A Grave-related advertisements that are tailored to you based upon your interests or online behaviors. Any such targeted ads placed on our behalf will contain information on or near it that informs you about the third party delivering you the ads and how to opt-out of receiving such ads in the future. If you wish to not have your information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) and [here](http://media1.ancestry.com/TE_optout.html?hideHeader=1) (you must do both to adequately opt-out). Please note that these links do not opt you out of being served advertising. Because occasionally the Find A Grave Websites may be partially advertiser supported, you may not "turn off" the advertising that appears on Find A Grave pages. You will continue to receive generic ads that may not be as relevant to you. If you are concerned about other interest-based ads you are receiving on other websites, you may want to visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> for additional opt-out information. Also, please note that if you delete, block or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice.

  6. To showcase your contributions: We may sometimes wish to highlight our Users' contributions to the Websites and may include your contribution in a highlighted section of one of the Websites. When we do so, we will attribute your contribution and provide a link to your member profile on the appropriate Websites. If you choose to post photos, bookmark graves, or contribute other content this activity will be visible to both registered and non-registered users of the Websites, for example via your member profile, and may also be made available on the Group Companies' websites. If you do not want this activity to be visible to other users or available on the Group Companies' websites you should not use the Websites in this way. 
  7. To run contests, surveys, & promotions: We may occasionally run contests, surveys, or other special promotions on our Websites in which we ask users for personal information (like an e-mail address or name) or demographic information (like a postcode, age, or income level). We use this data to run the contests and promotions and may also use it to send users promotional material about Find A Grave or third parties we deal with. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The participant's contact information is also used to contact him or her when necessary and may be shared with other companies for promotional purposes, but only with your prior permission and under the terms and conditions specified when you take part in the promotion. At any time, you may opt-out of receiving future mailings of this kind by following the unsubscribe instructions in each promotional communication or simply decline to take part in the promotions. 
  8. Use of mobile data. We use mobile analytics software to allow us to deliver you the Websites and better understand the functionality of our Websites. For example, if you are using the Find A Grave mobile application, this software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile app. 
  9. Transfers to other countries. Any personal information that we collect may be transferred to and stored and processed in other countries which may provide a different level of protection for personal data than in your country of residence. However, Find A Grave will take necessary measures to ensure that third parties receiving personal information will comply with the obligations set forth in this Privacy Statement. By allowing us to collect personal information about you, you specifically consent to the transfer, storage and processing of personal information. 

**3\. Will Find A Grave disclose any of my personal information to third parties?**

Find A Grave will not disclose any of your personal information to third parties without requiring your consent except in the limited circumstances which are set out below.

  1. In these scenarios: (a) with your knowledge and any relevant consents; (b) as described in this statement; (c) as may be required or permitted by law, regulatory authorities, legal process or to protect the rights, property, safety, confidentiality, or reputation of Find A Grave, its Group Companies, or other users (including outside your country of residence); (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to prevent fraud or cybercrime; or (f) to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. 
  2. To Group Companies: We may share your personal information with our Group Companies so that they may use personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement. Find A Grave is responsible for the management of the jointly used personal information. The Group Companies use personal data subject to similar Privacy Statements. Additionally, as our business continues to grow and change, we might restructure, buy, or sell subsidiaries or business units. In these transactions, customer information is often one of the transferred assets, remaining subject to promises made in then prevailing privacy statements. Also, in the event that Find A Grave, or substantially all of its assets or stock are acquired, transferred, disposed of (in whole or part and including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings), personal information will as a matter of course be one of the transferred assets. 
  3. Third-party service providers: Under the protection of appropriate agreements, we may disclose personal information to third party service providers we use to perform various tasks for us including for the purposes of data storage, consolidation, retrieval, analysis or the effective management of customer information. For example, we use third parties to process payments from you and to help manage our Website and relationships with you. These third-parties are only given access to that information needed to perform their support functions, and are prohibited from using it for other purposes. Processors include affiliated and unaffiliated service providers in in the United States, Europe and in other jurisdictions. With respect to processors outside Europe, we attempt to ensure adequate safeguards for your personal information, as required by applicable law and endeavour to confirm that they have adopted, are subject to, or are contractually obligated to comply with the principles and objectives of this Privacy Statement.

Please note: If you click away from our Websites to visit the site of any third party advertiser or sponsor, you may be asked for your payment card or other personal information in order to purchase or use products and services offered. These companies have their own privacy and data collection practices. We have no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. You should therefore review their privacy notices carefully if you have concerns about how your information may be used.

**4\. What about non-personal information, "cookies" and social media features?**

  1. Non-personal information. When you visit our Websites, we may automatically collect information that does not identify you ("Non-Personal Information"), such as the website from which you have come to our Websites, your Media Access Control address, your computer type, screen resolution, operating system version and Internet browser, as well as information based on your interaction with the Websites to deliver the Websites to you and to help diagnose problems with our server. Because Non-Personal Information does not personally identify you, we may use such Non-Personal Information for any purpose, including sharing that information with our Group Companies and with other third parties, unless we are required to treat any such information as personal under applicable law.

We may also collect Non-Personal Information such as demographic data, age groups, and your geographic areas, etc. Non-Personal Information also includes personal information that has been aggregated in a manner such that the end-product does not personally identify you or any other user of the Websites, for example, by using personal information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code or who are female. This technology helps us compile aggregated statistics about our users and their use of the Websites. We use these statistics to improve the design and content of the Websites and to prepare and deliver our marketing programs. We also aggregate personal information into Non-Personally Identifiable information. In some instances, we may combine Non-Personal Information with personal information (such as combining your name with your geographical location). If we do combine any Non-Personal Information with personal information, the combined information will be treated by us as personal information, as long as it is combined, and its use by us will be subject to this Privacy Statement.

  2. Cookies and other tracking technologies. We (either ourselves or our appointed third parties) place cookies or pixel tags (small tracking files) on your computer, to analyze the use of our Websites and optimize and customize the Websites and your experience. Our cookies and tags do not extract any contact, private information or other personal information from your computer's memory, but rather record only limited personal information your computer sends us when you visit our Websites, such as your IP address. Cookies enable our server to recognize or "remember" who you are each time you return. Find A Grave may make limited use of cookies to deliver content and advertisements specific to your interests. For instance, they may be used to retain your personal preferences, hold session information, or save your password so it doesn't have to be re-entered each time you login. These technologies may also be used to see how you move around and interact with the Websites or may be used to show you relevant ads either on or off the Websites.

Please note that Find A Grave may allow third-party advertisers that are presenting advertisements for us to set and access their cookies or pixel tags on your computer or otherwise use your information. The advertisers' use of cookies and pixel tags is subject to their own privacy policies, not this Privacy Statement.

You can erase or block cookies from your computer if you want to (your help screen or manual should tell you how to do this), but certain portions of the Websites may not work correctly or at all if you set your browser not to accept cookies. To learn more about Cookies and other tracking technologies please click [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

  3. Social media features. Our Websites include social media features, such as "AddThis" on FindAGrave.com, which allows you to share Find A Grave content via Facebook, Twitter, email or numerous other social media platforms, and Apple's built-in sharing functionality on the iOS Find A Grave mobile application. These features may also collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Websites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it. 

**5\. Managing your privacy settings**

You can control how you share some personal information such as whether other users can see your email address or send you messages on your member page, by changing the settings of your member profile, which you can access by clicking on your Public name on the upper right corner on FindAGrave.com or by clicking on your Screen name on the mobile application.

**6\. How do you access, report, change, correct or delete information about yourself or your family?**

  1. Your profile. Any information that you have added into your member profile is controlled by you and can be accessed, amended or deleted by you at any time by accessing your member profile. To request that any unauthorized profile about you be deleted, please contact us at info@findagrave.com to request removal. 
  2. Information in historical documents. Find A Grave obtains collections of historical documents from various sources. Find A Grave and its Group Companies and agents take reasonable steps to assure that the documents do not include sensitive personal information about living individuals. Unfortunately we are not able to change the information in records and you need to contact the entity responsible for such records. We will however consider requests for removal of personal information from the searchable indexes of the records we hold on a case-by-case basis. 
  3. User provided content. Find A Grave permits its users to upload documents and photos and to post commentary related to photos and historical and other content. Although we prohibit users from posting content that violates the privacy rights of others, Find A Grave does not edit or approve user provided content. It is possible that another user will post information that you consider to be private. You are not able to delete or amend this information and if it has been posted by another user then you should contact them through the Websites and try and resolve the issue between you. If you cannot resolve the issue then you should contact us at [info@findagrave.com](mailto:info@findagrave.com). 
  4. Your opinions and comments: To request removal of your personal information from community discussions or chats on the Websites, contact us at info@findagrave.com and we will consider it for removal. 
  5. For disputes or issues with other personal information on the site about you: Find A Grave will maintain procedures consistent with applicable law for individuals to access their collected personal information and, when appropriate, correct or delete their personal information. If you wish to request access to and receive information about the personal information we maintain about you, update and correct inaccuracies in your personal information, have the information blocked or deleted, as appropriate, oppose (in case of legitimate reasons) the processing carried out with respect to your personal information or you wish to revoke consent you provided previously to the extent permitted by the law, (note please that the right to access personal information may be limited in some circumstances), you can contact us at info@findagrave.com. 
  6. Backup copies and shared data: Removed and deleted information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable time for our internal business purposes but will not be available to others. Please note that where you or we delete content or your account, copies of that information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent any such copy has been shared with others, was otherwise distributed pursuant to your privacy settings, or was copied or stored by other users, but you will no longer be identified with that content. Additionally, we may retain certain information to prevent identity theft and other misconduct even if deletion has been requested. If you have given third party applications or websites access to your information, they may retain your information to the extent permitted under their terms of service or privacy policies but they will no longer be able to access the information through our platform after you disconnect from them. 

**7\. Security**

Find A Grave places great importance on the security of all personally information associated with our users. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and interference and from unauthorized access, modification or disclosure of member data under our control. For example our security and privacy practices are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized personnel have access to personal information. We use secure server software to encrypt financial information you input before it is sent to us. In addition, we use encryption when transmitting geo-location data on your mobile device. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur however we use commercially reasonable efforts to prevent this. It is also important for you to guard against unauthorized access to your passwords and the unauthorized use of your computer.

**8\. Changes, updates, consent**

If we decide to change our Privacy Statement, we will issue an updated version of this Statement with an updated date legend on the Websites and/or notify you via email, the Websites or the mobile application or by other appropriate means prior to the change becoming effective if it is a significant change so that you will be aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it in accordance with applicable law. You should review our Privacy Statement regularly to ensure you are familiar with any changes to it. If you do not consent to any changes to our Privacy Statement and as a result you would like us not to use or hold your information in accordance with the revised terms, you may notify us here so we can discontinue your account.

**9\. Contact us about privacy**

If you have any questions or complaints about this Privacy Statement, Find A Grave's privacy practices or your dealings with the Websites, you can contact us at info@findagrave.com. You will need to provide us with sufficient details regarding your complaint, as well as any supporting information. We will investigate the issue and determine the steps that we will undertake to resolve your complaint and notify you in writing of our determination. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact the privacy regulator in your country. We will respond to all access requests within 30 days. For your protection, we will only implement such requests with respect to the personal information associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before considering your request.

**Need Help?**

**Email us at:** info@findagrave.com

**Or write to us at:**  
Find A Grave, Inc.  
Attn: Legal Department  
1300 W Traverse Parkway  
Lehi, UT 84043, United States
